ARMANDO J. HERRERA CANELON

1511 Newton Ave SE Atlanta, GA 30316

Phone: 786-515-7550 E-mail: armando.herrera91@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a versatile Quality Assurance (QA) / Business Analyst with the ability to quickly adapt to fast-paced working environments. My scope of expertise includes mobile, web and cloud application testing, project management methodologies, data analysis, budgeting and expense tracking. I have had the responsibility to lead quality assurance efforts for federal clients following the latest DevOps methodology practices. I am able to thoroughly analyze business rules and requirements in order to develop accurate test cases. In addition, I have designed and implemented systems operating procedures that facilitate project management office changes. In addition, I have also had experience in providing administrative and management support to numerous federal agencies. Flexibility and client satisfaction are my main priority.

CLEARANCES

Public Trust

EDUCATION

The George Washington University - Elliott School of International Affairs 2013

BA, International Affairs

Double Concentration in International Economics and Latin America

Minor in Geography

Miami Dade College - The Honors College, Dual Language Program, 2011

AA, International Relations

Magna Cum Laude Honors

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Admin Certification (In Progress), International Software Testing Qualifications Board Foundation Level Certification (In Progress), CONCUR Solutions Program-Proficient (Federal)

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Salesforce Administration (Pending Certification)
- DevOps Methodology proficiency
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Web and Mobile Application Functional & Regression Testing
- Data Staging
- Structured Query Language (SQL) Basic
- · Oracle Database

- Business Rule and Requirement Analysis
- Test Case Writing proficiency
- · Federal Event Cost and Budgeting
- Technical Writing
- Program Management Office
- Waterfall and Agile Methodology
- Requirements Management
- Meeting facilitation support

SOFTWARES

- Jira
- Salesforce
- TestRail

- Serena Business Manager
- Microsoft Office Applications
- ArcGIS- Basic Mapping and Spatial Analysis

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent)

Spanish (Native)

Portuguese (Conversational)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance (QA) Analyst, April 2018 - Present

Technology Solutions Provider, Inc. (TSPi), Reston, VA

U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA), Office of Disaster Assistance (ODA), Disaster Credit Management System (DCMS 2.0) Operations Center (OC)

QA Analyst supporting the Product Assurance team in the modernization testing efforts of DCMS 2.0 following the latest DevOps best practices. Test lead for the Production Support team responsible for evaluating production bugs and providing precise levels of efforts for testing. In charge of analyzing business requirements and acceptance criteria in order to accurately and efficiently corroborate bug resolution. Develop detailed test cases in order to functionally test all production bugs and meticulously record each corresponding test results in TestRail. Perform functional and integration testing of all DCMS 2.0 components. Test lead and Subject Matter Expert (SME) for the Loss Verification legacy mobile and new Salesforce applications. Report development and production bugs utilizing JIRA for tracking purposes while triaging with the relevant business analysts and developers. Conduct weekly regression test in order to guarantee environment code stability after builds.

Quality Assurance / Business Analyst III, March 2016 - April 2018

Technical Services Corporation, Arlington, VA

U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA), Office of Disaster Assistance (ODA), Disaster Credit Management System (DCMS) Operations Center (OC)

QA / Business Analyst directly supporting the QA team for the legacy and modernizations testing efforts of DCMS, Disaster Loan Application Portal (DLAP) and all sub-components. Loss Verification mobile application Subject Matter Expert for not only the QA team but also for all developers and functional analysts. Develop and maintain LV regression test case suite that covers end to end testing and is utilized by all testers in the QA team. Collaborate with end users to review, analyze and correctly document system requirements and user stories. Analyze business rules and requirements in order to develop accurate test cases for bug fixes and system change requests. Produce detailed reports on all test results and communicate findings to the relevant developers. Maintain around the clock support for disaster surge efforts, greatly improving turnaround time of emergency fixes. Responsible for generating and publishing DCMS monthly release notes containing detailed information about all system change requests and bug fixes included on each system deployment. Support the DCMS OC Program Management Office (PMO), and assist with the transition from waterfall methodology to Agile. Maintain communication between project stakeholders through recurring notification distributions. Update PMO system operating procedure and project related documentation.

Management Analyst, February 2015 - March 2016

Addx Corporation, Washington, DC

U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, Office of Small Disadvantage Business Utilization (OSDBU)

Management Analyst for the Direct Access Programs (DAP) and the National Veterans Small Business Engagement (NVSE) directly supporting the event planning team. Directed administrative policies to increase the team's productivity and workflow as well as tracked cost and budget estimations. Managed all nationwide Direct Access Programs event resources and expenses. Designed, implemented, and executed internal change management processes and documentation. Provided meeting facilitation and support to the NVSBE planning council briefings for the department's Deputy Chief of Staff and OSDBU Executive Director. Responsible for developing travel and expense reports for the Deputy Director and Direct Access Programs Director.

Executive Assistant, October 2014 - February 2015

Monterey Consultants, Inc., Washington, DC

U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, Office of Small Disadvantage Business Utilization (OSDBU)

Executive Assistant for the OSDBU Executive Director and Deputy Director. Scheduled and coordinated the logistical aspect of all briefings. Provided schedule and time management support. Managed travel expense reports for all federal staff in OSDBU. Organized and documented all business vendor meetings. Mediated all communication between the Executive Director and the Department's top leadership.

Business Analyst I, January 2014 - October 2014

Monterey Consultants, Inc., Washington, DC

U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, Program Management Center of Excellence (PMCOE)

Business Analyst I for the PMCOE; executed more than thirty webinars on program management and systems engineering topics, also known as Knowledge Areas that were relevant to the PMCOE. Administered and updated all Knowledge Areas membership databases. Analyzed and developed internal policies and strategies to increase workload productivity. Provided administrative support for all work streams pertaining to the PMCOE.

Adjunct Research Assistant, August 2013 - December 2013

The George Washington University Urban Sustainability Service-Learning Class, Washington, DC

The Urban Land Institute and the American Institute of Architects

Adjunct Research Assistant supporting the GW's Geography Urban Sustainability Department by researching green infrastructure and risk management practices of Miami-Dade County's Sustainability Plan. Researched proven sustainability approaches on other cities' sustainability plans and conceptualized the differences between them. Delivered weekly reports on the successes and failures of the county's sustainability plan and formulated comprehensive improvements. Consolidated policy briefings for project partners and provided analysis of sustainability development tactics.

Executive Assistant, June 2013 - August 2013

Nonin Medical, Inc., Miami, FL

Latin America Regional Sales Department

Executive Assistant for Nonin's Latin America Regional Sales Manager. Assisted the development of the company's business strategy for the regional sales and market expansion. Collected and

analyzed distributors sales throughout Latin America. Diagnosed the economic stability of countries in the region and identified business risks. Evaluated and analyzed the company's sales forecasts for the upcoming fiscal year. Arranged cyclical travel and coordinated all meetings. Translated contractual documentation.

Executive Assistant, September 2012 - December 2012

Open Society Foundation, Washington, DC

The Connect U.S. Fund, Fissile Material Working Group (FMWG)

Executive Assistant for the Fissile Material coordinator. Administered and edited FMWG's website and weekly newsletter. Researched current event topics related to nuclear proliferation. Scheduled stakeholder's meetings and provided meeting facilitation support. Processed all website inquiries and compiled frequently asked questions. Oversaw the logistical planning of the organization's annual fundraising event.